it's been an icon throughout history for good and for bad reasons. The earliest ones that we can trace are from ancient Greece and ancient Rome. The Middle Ages, you see a lot of monks that were wearing garments that were cape-like, with hoods attached, so therefore, "hoodies." Ladies in the 17th century would wear hoodies to kind of hide themselves when they were going to meet their lovers. And then, of course, there's the legend, there's fantasy. There's the image of the hoodie connected to the grim reaper. There's the image of the hoodie connected to the executioner. So there's the dark side of the hoodie. The modern incarnation of the hoodie -- a garment that's made usually of cotton jersey, that has a hood attached with a drawstring; sometimes it has a marsupial pocket -- was introduced in the 1930s by Knickerbocker Knitting Company. Now it's called Champion. It was meant to keep athletes warm. Of course, though, it was such a functional, comfortable garment that it was very rapidly adopted by workmen everywhere. And then, around the 1980s, it also gets adopted by hip-hop and B-boys, skateboarders, and it takes on this kind of youth street culture. It was, at the same time, super-comfortable, perfect for the streets and also had that added value of anonymity when you needed it. And then we have Mark Zuckerberg, who defies convention of respectable attire for businesspeople. But interestingly, it's also a way to show how power has changed. If you're wearing a two-piece suit, you might be the bodyguard. The real powerful person is wearing a hoodie with a T-shirt and jeans. It's easy to think of the physical aspects of the hoodie. You can immediately think of wearing the hood up, and you feel this warmth and this protection, but at the same time, you can also feel the psychological aspects of it. I mean, think of donning a hoodie, all of a sudden, you feel more protected, you feel that you are in your own shell. We know very well what the hoodie has come to signify in the past few years in the United States. When Trayvon Martin, a 17-year-old African-American kid, was shot by a neighborhood vigilante, and Million Hoodie Marches happened all over the United States, in which people wore hoodies with the hood up and marched in the streets against this kind of prejudice. It doesn't happen that often for a garment to have so much symbolism and history and that encompasses so many different universes as the hoodie. So, like all garments, especially all truly utilitarian garments, it is very basic in its design. But at the same time, it has a whole universe of possibilities attached.
es un icono a través de la historia por razones buenas y malas. Las capuchas más tempranas que encontramos proceden de la antigua Grecia y la antigua Roma. Durante la Edad Media, muchos monjes llevaban trajes parecidos a túnicas con "capa", de allí, "capucha". En el siglo XVII, las damas llevaban prendas con capuchas para esconderse en camino a estar con su amante. Y luego, claro, está la leyenda, la fantasía. La capucha se asocia con la Parca. La capucha se asocia con el verdugo. Así que la capucha tiene un lado oscuro. La encarnación moderna de la capucha... una prenda normalmente de jersey de algodón, que tiene una capucha pegada y tiene un cordón, a veces tiene bolsillo marsupial, fue presentada en los años 30 por Knickerbocker Knitting Company. Ahora se llama Champion. La idea era mantener la temperatura de los atletas. Pero claro, es una prenda tan funcional y cómoda que fue adoptada enseguida por obreros en todas partes. Y luego en los años 80, es adoptada también por el hip-hop y los b-boys, los skaters, y representa un tipo de cultura urbana. Es a la vez súper cómoda, perfecta para llevar en la calle, y tiene ese valor adicional de anonimato cuando la necesitas. Y luego tenemos a Mark Zuckerberg, que desafía las normas de vestimenta respetable para la gente de negocios. Curiosamente, también es una manera de demostrar cómo ha cambiado el poder. Si llevas un traje de dos piezas, quizás eres el guardaespaldas, y la persona poderosa de verdad lleva una capucha con una camiseta y jeans. Es fácil imaginar los aspectos físicos de esta prenda. Pensamos automáticamente en la capucha puesta, en sentir su calor y su protección. Pero al mismo tiempo, podemos sentir los aspectos psicológicos. Piensa en ponerte una capucha, y de repente sientes más protección, sientes que estás en tu propia cáscara. Sabemos muy bien lo que ha significado la capucha en los últimos años en EE.UU. Cuando Trayvon Martin, un chico afroestadounidense de 17 años, fue asesinado por un miembro de una patrulla vecinal, hubo manifestaciones "Million Hoodie Marches" por todo Estados Unidos, en las cuales las personas llevaban prendas con capuchas y desfilaron por las calles en contra a ese tipo de prejuicio. No ocurre mucho que una prenda encarne tanto simbolismo e historia, y que abarque tantos diferentes universos como la capucha. Como todas las prendas, particularmente las prendas verdaderamente utilitarias, la capucha es muy básica en su diseño. Pero al mismo tiempo, lleva consigo un universo entero de posibilidades.